martinjosephgormley@gmail.com martygormley.com github.com/martyjg linkedin.com/in/martygormley +4478 4395 6541

Profile

My drive for web development derives from my enjoyment of problem-solving, the opportunity of learning how to tackle these problems from different perspectives and the satisfaction of making quality products. I'm searching for a position where I can work and learn creatively in a progressive and modern team.

Skills

Proficient with...
HTML5, CSS,
JavaScript, ¡Query,
Ruby, Ruby on Rails,
Node.js, Express.js,
Angular, Mongoose,
Git

Experience with...
AJAX, Socket.io,
Mocha, Chai, Sinatra,
Bootstrap, Foundation,
Pure, PostgresQL,
Python

Currently playing with... React.js, Arduino, Processing

Experience

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive | July 2015 - Present The WDI scheme provided me with an intensive and satisfying initial learning environment in web development. The course involves twelve weeks of taught lessons which range across everything necessary to get on the technical level of a Junior Developer. The projects I completed during the course allowed me to experience the process of conceptualisation, planning, development and deployment. The course has given me experience of an agile process and git/github. Most importantly, WDI has given me the tools to teach myself any new technology with confidence.

Unicorns In Tech - Events and Community Manager | October 2014 - June 2015 Organising the Unicorns In Tech community gave me experience of working alone and in a team to see large project through from start to completion. Arranging speakers and seeking new members provided me with an insight into the tech and startup world and how to impartially discover an important topic or current technology.

Education

General Assembly - Web Development Immersive | July 2015 - Present Goldsmiths College (UoL) - BSc Psychology | September 2011 - July 2014 Lumen Christi College - A*AAB at A-level | September 2009 - June 2011

Portfolio

MySpace

A social networking app where you can present your personality/interests and connect with friends. This was my final project at GA and I thought it would be interesting to take what was a new concept from the previous decade and recreate it using modern technologies. It provided me with an excellent opportunity to practice and present a lot of which I had learnt at GA.



Tech - An app built on Node & Express. I used Angular for a frontend framework and Mongoose to handle my database.

VibeRate

An app where a user can pitch an idea to a group of friends and vote positively or negatively on ideas pitches to them. This was a group project built in 5 days. My role was Git Master and to assist the developers when they faced issues via pair programming. I had an opportunity to learn version control in a team setting and managed our team effectively.



Tech - an API built on Node & Express with an emoji API. Front-end built with JavaScript.

ScreenCapp

An app that lets a user share their favourite movie screenshots and offer a caption contest to other users. A user can post, view, edit and delete screenshots and have many social options such as commenting, voting up comments and following other users. A user can also login using Facebook authentication.



Tech - An app built with Ruby on Rails and a postgresSQL database with Facebook OAuth, SASS, Carrierwave.

LemonadeStand

A JavaScript made for our initial project at GA. LemonStand is a simple game where a player must purchase ingredients then depending on the forecasted weather, select a location to sell their lemonade. The game continues if the player can keep their balance above zero. LemonadeStand is written in pure JavaScript and I also drew some graphics/animations for the game.



Interests

When not staring at a screen and making web apps, I can usually be found staring at a screen and playing video games. For weekend fun I'm always on the lookout for new cafes, bars and parties so please send any tips my way. Other extra-curricular activities include rummaging in charity clothes shops and checking out gallery openings or launch parties.